<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>Quanta of Entropy</title>
  
  <link href="/blog/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  
  <link href="https://entron.github.io/blog/"/>
  <updated>2016-12-19T10:22:35.296Z</updated>
  <id>https://entron.github.io/blog/</id>
  
  <author>
    <name>Cheng Guo</name>
    
  </author>
  
  <generator uri="http://hexo.io/">Hexo</generator>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Optimal Exchange Rate for Importers and Exporters</title>
    <link href="https://entron.github.io/blog/2016/12/13/Optimal-Exchange-Rate-for-Importers-and-Exporters/"/>
    <id>https://entron.github.io/blog/2016/12/13/Optimal-Exchange-Rate-for-Importers-and-Exporters/</id>
    <published>2016-12-13T22:12:39.000Z</published>
    <updated>2016-12-19T10:22:35.296Z</updated>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am reading a book about basic economics recently. One chapter of this book is about exchange rate between currencies.  A simplified picture is showing below.</p>
<img src="/blog/2016/12/13/Optimal-Exchange-Rate-for-Importers-and-Exporters/best-exchange-rate.png" alt="best-exchange-rate.png" title="">
<a id="more"></a>
<p>The x-axis is the price of a currency measured by another currency, in other words the exchange rate. For example in our plot we can imagine it as the price of 1 US dollar in Chinese yuan. Same with other goods, there are supply and demands of dollar in a country trading with US, such as China. The higher the price the more the supply and the less the demand. This is show by the lines AI and BJ respectively. The exporters need to sell the dollar they earned thus they are the suppliers and the importers need to buy dollar first so that they can by goods produced in the US thus they are the demander. </p>
<p>In a free market, the exchange rate will be settled at the point E where demand and supply are the same. One very interesting fact (may also be surprising fact for some) is that this price E is also the optimal price if the country wants to maximize the profit of its importers and exporters. To see the reason first we need to note that the line AI is the cost of the exporters to get the dollars, that is the price of the goods they sell to US measured by yuan. The suppliers only wants to export goods and sell the dollar on the right of line AI.  For importers the line BJ is their cost for the imported goods which they will see to the domestic market. Only on the left of the line BC they will make a profit. You can’t buy more the the supply willing to sell and you can’t sell more than the demander willing to buy, therefor the maximum trade you can make freely is the overlap of the two regions which is the triangle ABC. The area of the triangle ACE is the profit of the exporters and the profit of importers is the area of BCE.</p>
<p>After learned this, I am wondering why would a government manipulate the exchange rate rather than doing nothing and maximize the whole country’s profit for free? I guess there could be many reasons to them, but probably the deepest reason (like the subconscious of the country) is that the influence of importers and exporters to the government is not balanced. If the importers have a stronger influence, they could convince the government to set the price at D instead of E. In this case the total trade (profit) is reduced to the area ABGF from ABC, however the profit of the importers are increased from BCE to BGFD in the expense of the importers profit which reduced from ACE to AFD.</p>
<p>What the price should be if the importers (exporters) has total control of the government and want to maximize their profit? Of course, this will never happen in real world, but let me try to answer this question in the above simplified world just out of curiosity.</p>
<p>With some middle school geometry and algebra we can solve this problem as following. We take the problem to maximize importers profit for example. </p>
<p>$$<br>\frac{FD}{CE} = \frac{AD}{AE} \Rightarrow FD = \frac{CE}{AE} AD<br>$$</p>
<p>and</p>
<p>$$<br>CH = CE - HE =CE - FD = CE -  \frac{CE}{AE} AD<br>$$</p>
<p>and</p>
<p>$$<br>\frac{FG}{AB} = \frac{CH}{CE} = 1 - \frac{AD}{AE} \Rightarrow FG = AB - \frac{AB}{AE}AD<br>$$</p>
<p>The area of the trapezoid FGDB is</p>
<p>$$<br>S = (FG + AB)FD /2<br>$$</p>
<p>Combine the above equations we get</p>
<p>$$<br>S = -\frac{(AE+AB)CE}{2 AE^2} AD^2 + \frac{AB \times CE}{AE} AD<br>$$</p>
<p>$S$ is maximum at </p>
<p>$$<br>DE = AB -AD =  \frac{AB^2}{AB + AE}<br>$$</p>
<p>This is the amount by which one should reduce the dollar price (artificially stronger yuan) so that the importer can maximize their benefit. To maximize the exporters benefit, D will be on the right of the optimal price E and this is a symmetrical to the above calculations and we can easily see in this case</p>
<p>$$<br>DE =  \frac{AB^2}{AB + BE}<br>$$</p>
<p>This is the amount by which one should increase the dollar price (artificially weaker yuan) so that the exporter can maximize their benefit.</p>
]]></content>
    
    <summary type="html">
    
      &lt;p&gt;I am reading a book about basic economics recently. One chapter of this book is about exchange rate between currencies.  A simplified picture is showing below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/blog/2016/12/13/Optimal-Exchange-Rate-for-Importers-and-Exporters/best-exchange-rate.png&quot; alt=&quot;best-exchange-rate.png&quot; title=&quot;&quot;&gt;
    
    </summary>
    
    
      <category term="economics" scheme="https://entron.github.io/blog/tags/economics/"/>
    
  </entry>
  
</feed>
